{
  "-L576FEC4L8skxEgO5Yd" : {
    "back" : "* Regional ACs\n* Commune ACs\n* Single Vineyard *Premier Cru* ACs\n* Single Vineyard *Grand Cru* ACs\n\nUnlike __Bordeaux__, each individual *Premier Cru* or *Grand Cru* vineyard has their own AC.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "front" : "List the hierarchy of __Burgundy__ appellations in order from lowest to highest.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEC4L8skxEgO5Yf" : {
    "back" : "*Bourgogne Aligoté AC* are mostly high in acidity and low in alcohol.\n\nThey are mainly produced in __Chablis__, and a few villages in __Côte d'Or__ and __Côte Chalonnaise__.",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "front" : "Describe *Bourgogne Aligoté AC* (5 points)",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEDLfYrbW0G5RR_" : {
    "back" : "Approx. *1/3* of all wine production in __Burgundy__ is from *Commune ACs* such as __Chablis__ or __Gevrey-Chambertin__.",
    "diffculty" : "normal",
    "front" : "What percentage of __Burgundy__ wine production is by communal or village appellations?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEDLfYrbW0G5RRb" : {
    "back" : "There are over *600* *Premiers Crus* in __Burgundy__, spread between __Chablis__, __Côte d'Or__ and __Côte Chalonnaise__.\n\n*Premier Cru* wines account for approx. *1/10th* of wine production in __Burgundy__.",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "How many *Premiers Crus* are there in __Burgundy__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEDLfYrbW0G5RRd" : {
    "back" : "__Burgundy__ has approx. *100* ACs (compared to approx. *60* ACs in __Bordeaux__).\n\nAlthough it has *less than 1/3* of the area under vine compared to its western cousin.",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "How many ACs are there in __Burgundy__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEDLfYrbW0G5RRf" : {
    "back" : "* __Burgundy__ vineyard names are attached to a specific plot of land\n* communes in __Burgundy__ with *Premier Cru* and *Grand Cru* vineyards have their own ACs\n* most __Burgundy__ vineyards have many owners, with individual parcel of vines, producing individual wine styles\n\n* __Bordeaux__ château names are trademarks, owners can add vineyard plots anywhere in the appellation\n* *Grand Cru* and *Premier Cru* are not part of the __Bordeaux__ AC system",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "What are the fundamental differences between the __Bordeaux__ and __Burgundy__ AC structures?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEDLfYrbW0G5RRh" : {
    "back" : "BEAUNE\n*Grèves* \nAppellation Beaune Premier Cru Contrôlée\n\n*OR* \n\nBEAUNE\n*Grèves Premier Cru* \nAppellation Beaune Premier Cru Contrôlée",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "What are two different ways __Burgundy__ *Premier Cru* wines can state their status on the label.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEDLfYrbW0G5RRj" : {
    "back" : "__Burgundy__ has perfected four technqiues synonmous with premium *Chardonnay* production around the world:\n\n* barrel fermentation\n* barrel aging (usually 6-9 months)\n* malolactic fermentation (MLF)\n* use of lees during maturation",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "What are four key characteristics of *white Burgundy* wine making?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEE7p3rRzGwmd5H" : {
    "back" : "* northern *continental* climate, with severe winters and hot summers\n* autumns are cool with frequent rainfall at harvest time\n* lower annual rainfall compared to __Bordeaux__ (650mm vs 890mm)\n* *spring frosts* may appear as late as May in __Chablis__\n* summer rains may cause *grey rot* and localised *hailstorms* ",
    "difficult" : "easy",
    "front" : "Describe __Burgundy__'s climate and growing conditions. (5 points)",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEE7p3rRzGwmd5J" : {
    "back" : "There are two key soil types found in __Burgundy__:\n\n* *calcareous clayey* - predominately *Chardonnay*\n* limy marl - mainly *Pinot Noir* \n\nHowever, growers tend to plant whatever sells - ie. *Chardonnay* has replaced *Pinot Noir* in most of __Chassagne-Montrachet__ even though the soils are *calcareous clay*.",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "What kind of soils can be found in __Burgundy__ vineyards and what grape varieties are typically planted on these?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEE7p3rRzGwmd5L" : {
    "back" : "Mid-slope sites in __Burgundy__ catch deepest layer of slope-wash and act as sun-traps.\n\nThis is important because high quality __Burgundy__ *Pinot Noir* and *Chardonnay* wines are sensitive to the subtle variations in *terroir*, such as steepness and direction of the slopes, depth, drainage, heat retention and mineral content of the soils.",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "Why the best sites in __Burgundy__ often found mid-slope?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEE7p3rRzGwmd5N" : {
    "back" : "Correct Answer: *(D) West*\n\nMain vineyards in __Burgundy__ lie on the eastern fringe of the __Massif Central__, acting as its protective barrier.",
    "difficult" : "easy",
    "front" : "The majority of __Burgundy__ vineyards are protected by the central __Massif__ mountains to its:\n\nA) North\nB) East\nC) South\nD) West",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEE7p3rRzGwmd5P" : {
    "back" : "1. *Pinot Noir*\n2. *Chardonnay*\n3. *Aligoté*\n4. *Gamay*",
    "difficult" : "easy",
    "front" : "What are the *4* main grape varieties grown in __Burgundy__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEE7p3rRzGwmd5R" : {
    "back" : "* *red fruits* (cherry, raspberry, strawberry) when young\n* *vegetal*, *savoury* and *gamey* notes when mature\n* medium to high tannins\n* medium to high acidity\n* full bodied",
    "difficult" : "easy",
    "front" : "Describe characteristics of a classic __Burgundy__ *Pinot Noir* wine.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEF1LchHqfF8eUW" : {
    "back" : "__Chablis__ - lean, steely, high-acidity\n\n__Côte d'Or__ - rich, ripe, creamy-buttery, complex and expressive\n\n__Mâcon__ - full-bodied, ripe fruits",
    "difficult" : "easy",
    "front" : "How do *Chardonnay* wines from different regions across __Burgundy__ differ?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEF1LchHqfF8eUY" : {
    "back" : "*Aligoté* accounts for about 5% of total vineyard area in __Burgundy__, *Gamay* accounts for approximately 10% .\n\n*Gamay* now only contributes to *Bourgogne Grand Ordinaire* and *Bourgogne Passetoutgrains AC* wines and red wines in __Mâconnais__.",
    "difficult" : "hard",
    "front" : "How much vine does *Aligoté* and *Gamay* account for in __Burgundy__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEF1LchHqfF8eU_" : {
    "back" : "Answer: (A)\n\n__Burgundy__ vines are one of the most densely planted in the world, at up to *12,000 per hectare*.",
    "difficult" : "easy",
    "front" : "Vines in __Burgundy__ are one of the\n\n(A) most\n(B) more\n(C) sparely\n(D) least\n\ndensely planted in the world.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEF1LchHqfF8eUb" : {
    "back" : "Most vineyards in __Burgundy__ train their vines low along wires using the *single Guyot* system.\n\nSome growers in __Hautes-Côte__ may use a higher-trained vines system.",
    "difficult" : "easy",
    "front" : "What vine training methods are used in __Burgundy__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEF1LchHqfF8eUd" : {
    "back" : "__Burgundy__ has cool autumns and cold winters that may cause fermentation to stop if the musts are not warmed.\n\nThis is a threat for even cool-fermented white wines in __Chablis__ where temperatures can fall low enough to cause a problem.",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "What impact does __Burgundy__'s cool climate have on wine making?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEGCkGXFwel8N2g" : {
    "back" : "* cold-soaking musts before fermentation\n* traditional open vat fermentation, with pumping over of the juice or punching down of the cap\n* destemming may occur, with some winemakers retaining a portion of stems to provide a source of tannins",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "Describe common red wine making techniques in __Burgundy__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEGCkGXFwel8N2i" : {
    "back" : "Example:\n\n*BEAUNE 1er Cru\nAppellation Beaune Premier Cru Contrôlée*\n\nThe *1er Cru* designation represents wines blended together from various *Premier Cru* vineyards within a village.",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "What does a __Burgundy__ *1er Cru* on the label indicate?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEGCkGXFwel8N2k" : {
    "back" : "There are __34__ *Grand Cru* vineyards in __Burgundy__:\n\n* *33* in __Côte d'Or__\n* *1* in __Chablis__ (spread over 7 adjoining plots of land)",
    "difficult" : "hard",
    "front" : "How many *Grand Cru* vineyards are there in __Burgundy__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEGCkGXFwel8N2m" : {
    "back" : "*Example:* \n\nCORTON-CHARLEMAGNE\nGrand Cru\nAppellation Corton-Charlemagne Contrôlée\n\n*Grand Cru* can be identified by the fact that the vineyard name stands alone on the label. It is unnecessary to state which village the wine is from.",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "Give an example of a __Burgundy__ *Grand Cru* label.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEH-rMjwEEq2RdV" : {
    "back" : "Mayors of certain villages in __Burgundy__ added the name of their most famous vineyards to increase the prestige of their simple village wines.\n\nExample: *Grand Cru* vineyard of __Corton__ added to the village of __Aloxe__ to make *Aloxe-Corton*.",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "What do __Côte d'Or__ commune names like *Aloxe-Corton* and *Nuits-Saint-George* signify?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEH-rMjwEEq2RdX" : {
    "back" : "__Chablis__ appellation originally required vineyards to lie on *limestone* overlaid with *Kimmeridgian clay*.\n\nThe appellation now extends to vineyards on *Portlandian clay*.",
    "difficult" : "hard",
    "front" : "What soil types qualify for __Chablis__ appellation status?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEH-rMjwEEq2RdZ" : {
    "back" : "*Frost* is __Chablis__ growers' biggest challenge.\n\nBetter vineyards install aspersion sprinkler systems as a protective measure. Heaters and helicopters are also used to circulate air and dissipate frost pockets.",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "What is the biggest climate problem faced by __Chablis__ growers? What methods are used to mitigate that problem?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEH-rMjwEEq2Rda" : {
    "back" : "There are *7* __Chablis__ *Grand Cru AC* vineyards, all lie on one hillside across the river from the town of __Chablis__:\n\n1. *Les Clos* \n2. *Vaudésir* \n3. *Valmur* \n4. *Les Preuses* \n5. *Bougros* \n6. *Blanchot* \n7. *Grenouilles* ",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "List all __Chablis__ *Grand Cru AC* vineyards.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEI07qKwgWEt3Wo" : {
    "back" : "__Chablis AC__ - austere; green-plum/green-apple fruit; high acidity\n\n__Chablis Premier AC__ - riper fruit (lemon citrus); more body, softer and creamier texture (compared to *Chablis AC*); stony or smoky minerality; high acidity\n\n__Chablis Grand Cru AC__ - integrated oak flavours; smoky comlex aromas; long finish; refreshing high acidity",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "How do wine styles differ between __Chablis__ appellation levels?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEI07qKwgWEt3Wq" : {
    "back" : "__Côte d'Or__ vineyards lie in a narrow band on slopes facing east or southeast for maximum morning sun exposure and enjoys the protection of the __Morvan__ hills behind them.\n\nThe *Côte* is split into north and south halves:\n* North: __Côte de Nuits__ \n* South: __Côte de Beaune__",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "Describe the geographic features of the __Côte d'Or__ region.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEI07qKwgWEt3Ws" : {
    "back" : "Answer: (B) *limestone* and *marl* \n\nSoils in __Côte d'Or__ is a mix of *limestone* and *marl* (a calcium-rich clay). \n\n*Limestone* provides vines with nutrients that make them grow better and produce sweeter grapes.\n\n*Clay* soils tend to stay cooler and retains water, important factors for full-bodied bold wines.",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "What is the predominant soil types in the *Côte d'Or* region?\n\nA. *sandy clay* \nB. *limestone* and *marl* \nC. *silt clay* \nD. *slate* ",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEI07qKwgWEt3Wu" : {
    "back" : "__Côte d'Or__ predominantly uses the *Guyot* pruning method.",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "What pruning methods are used in __Côte d'Or__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEI07qKwgWEt3Ww" : {
    "back" : "All red *Grands Crus* (except __Corton__) are produced in __Côte de Nuits__.\n\nAll white *Grands Crus* (except __Musigny Blanc__) are produced in __Côte de Beaune__.",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "How is *Grands Crus* production distributed in the __Côte d'Or__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEJ-4qqxdt-fVRz" : {
    "back" : "__Gevrey Chambertin AC__ *Grand Crus*:\n\n* *Chambertin AC* \n* *Chambertin Clos de Bèze AC* ",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "List the *Grand Crus* of __Gevrey Chambertin AC__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEJ-4qqxdt-fVS0" : {
    "back" : "__Vosne-Romanée AC__ *Grand Crus*:\n\n* *Romanée-Conti AC* \n* *La Tâche AC* \n* *La Romanée AC* ",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "List the *Grands Crus* of __Vosne-Romanée AC__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEJ-4qqxdt-fVS2" : {
    "back" : "1. *Gevrey Chambertin AC* \n2. *Vougeot AC* \n3. *Vosne-Romanée AC* \n4. *Nuits-Saint-Georges AC* ",
    "difficult" : "normal",
    "front" : "Name the 4 most important villages in __Côte de Nuits__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEJ-4qqxdt-fVS4" : {
    "back" : "*18* villages produce wine under *Bourgogne Hautes-Côtes de Nuits AC* in the hills behind the vineyards of the Côte.",
    "difficult" : "hard",
    "front" : "How many villages produce wine under the regional appellation *Bourgogne Hautes-Côtes de Nuits AC*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEKC69su77KB1ZL" : {
    "back" : "The most important villages (and their *Grands Crus*) in __Côte de Beaune__ are:\n\n1. __Aloxe-Corton AC__ (*Corton AC*, *Corton-Charlemagne AC*)\n2. __Beaune AC__ \n3. __Pommard AC__ \n4. __Volnay AC__ \n5. __Meursault AC__ \n6. __Puligny-Montrachet AC__ (*Le Montrachet AC*)\n7. __Chassagne-Montrachet AC__ (*Le Montrachet AC*)",
    "difficult" : "hard",
    "front" : "Name the *7* important villages in __Côte de Beaune__ (and list their *Grands Crus*).",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEKC69su77KB1ZN" : {
    "back" : "__New Zealand__ first introduced labelling laws in 2006 with the *Geographical Indication (Wine and Spirit) Registration Act* was passed.",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "front" : "When did __New Zealand__ first passed wine labelling laws?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEMcmCGgWlTeYa2" : {
    "back" : "__New Zealand__ had approx. 30,000 hectares under vine in 2010.",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "front" : "How much land is under vine in __New Zealand__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEMcmCGgWlTeYa4" : {
    "back" : "2016 or earlier - 75% rule for grape varieties\n\nAfter 2007 - 85% rule if a label states the wine is from a particular grape variety, vintage or area\n*(does not apply to wines sold in bulk)*",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "front" : "What are the labelling requirements in *New Zealand*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEMcmCGgWlTeYa6" : {
    "back" : "Most of __New Zealand__ has a *cool to moderate maritime* climate due to the surrounding Pacific ocean, except:\n\n* *warm maritime* climate in the far north around __Auckland__\n* *moderate to cool continental* climate in __Central Otago__",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "front" : "What is __New Zealand__'s growing climate?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEMcmCGgWlTeYa8" : {
    "back" : "__Auckland__ has a *warm maritime* climate, with hot humid summers, and moderate, wet winters with temperatures rarely below 10°C.",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "front" : "Describe the climate in the area around __Auckland__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEMcmCGgWlTeYaA" : {
    "back" : "__New Zealand__ white varietals:\n\n1. *Sauvignon Blanc* (~50% of plantings)\n2. *Chardonnay*\n3. *Pinot Gris*\n4. *Riesling*",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "front" : "List the 4 white varietals with significant plantings in __New Zealand__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FENapFfzFmOs39p" : {
    "back" : "__Marlborough__'s benchmark *Sauvignon Blanc* expression has:\n\n* intense aromas of *gooseberry* and *capsicum*\n* often with notes of *herbal*, *passion fruit*, *tomato*, or *stony minerals*\n* occasional hints of *creamy oak*\n\nBetter wines with intense concentration and acidity can develop *asparagus* notes in the bottle.",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "front" : "Describe a __Marlborough__ *Sauvignon Blanc*.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FENapFfzFmOs39r" : {
    "back" : "*Merlot* and *Cabernet Sauvignon* - blended together in __Bordeaux__ style blends\n\n*Syrah* - high quality __Rhône__ style wines only in the warmest sites",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "front" : "What other black varietals are planted in __New Zealand__ aside from *Pinot Noir*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FENapFfzFmOs39t" : {
    "back" : "__New Zealand__ has a combination of *cool to moderate* temperatures, intense sunshine, and large *diurnal ranges*.\n\nThis combination allows grapes to reach high levels of sugar ripeness while retaining acidity and fresh, intense, aromatic flavours.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "front" : "What is special about __New Zealand__'s growing environment?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FENapFfzFmOs39v" : {
    "back" : "* vine vigour due to fertile flatlands\n* *Phylloxera*\n* fungal diseases in the north of the North Island",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "front" : "What viticultural problems do __New Zealand__ grape growers face?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FENapFfzFmOs39x" : {
    "back" : "Factors that contribute to 'purity of fruit' characteristics:\n\n* hygiene and temperature control\n* anaerobic winemaking\n* screencaps\n\n*(more than 90% of __New Zealand__ wines are closed with screencaps)*",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "front" : "What modern wine making techniques contribute to the 'purity of fruit' characteristic __New Zealand__ wines are known for?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FENapFfzFmOs39z" : {
    "back" : "Logistical challenges:\n\nLocal winery capacity cannot keep up with increasing vineyard areas, requiring grapes or must to be transported long distances for processing.",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "front" : "What viniculture challenges are driving up production costs in __New Zealand__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FENapFfzFmOs3A0" : {
    "back" : "Area north of __Auckland__, varieties grown:\n\n* *Cabernet Sauvignon*\n* *Merlot*\n* *Chardonnay*",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "front" : "Where did the wine industry start in __New Zealand__? What varietals are now grown there?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEOC00Iul1k_SnC" : {
    "back" : "__Hawke's Bay__:\n\n* is situated in an *estuary plain*\n* is warmest of the main __New Zealand__ growing areas\n* has the longest sunshine hours",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "front" : "What is special about the __Hawke's Bay__ vineyard area?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEOC00Iul1k_SnE" : {
    "back" : "__Gimblett Gravels__ has a high reputation for __Bordeaux__ style *Merlot* and *Cabernet Sauvignon* blends.\n\nIt has a well-drained, heat absorbing gravel soil on the valley floor of __Hawke's Bay__.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "front" : "What wine style is __Gimblett Gravels__ known for and why?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEOC00Iul1k_SnG" : {
    "back" : "__Martinborough__ *Pinot Noir*\n\nFactors that allow *Pinot Noir* to reach full sugar ripeness and retain flavour complexity and intensity are:\n\n* free draining, low fertility soils\n* cooler climate than rest of North Island\n* large diurnal range",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "front" : "Which __Wairarpa__ wine style has a global reputation? Why?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEOC00Iul1k_SnI" : {
    "back" : "__Marlborough__\n\n60% of __New Zealand__'s vineyard area are planted in the two adjacent *estuary valleys* of __Wairau__ and __Awatere__ in __Marlborough__.",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "front" : "Where is __Wairau__ and __Awatere__ located?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEOC00Iul1k_SnK" : {
    "back" : "__Marlborough__'s __Wairau__ has a climate similar to __Martinborough__ (cool maritime with large diurnal range).\n\n__Awatere__ tends to be drier, cooler, and windier.\n\nFrost is a risk in __Marlborough__.",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "front" : "Describe __Marlborough__'s growing climate.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEOC00Iul1k_SnM" : {
    "back" : "__North Wairau__ with gravelly soils produce *Sauvignon Blanc* with pronounced *capsicum*.\n\n__South Wairau__ is hotter and gives overripe, almost tropical flavours.\n\n__Awatere__ *Sauvignons* have higher acidity and distinctively pungent *tomato* character due to drier, cooler, windier conditions.",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "front" : "Why do different parts of __Marlborough__ produce different *Sauvignon Blancs*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEOC00Iul1k_SnO" : {
    "back" : "__Central Otago__ is a wide inland area in the foothills of the Southern Alps, with different valleys with different aspects, soils, and altitudes.\n\nUnlike the rest of __New Zealand__, it has a *continental* climate where *frost* is a risk in both spring and autumn.",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "front" : "Why is __Central Otago__ different from the rest of __New Zealand__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEOC00Iul1k_SnQ" : {
    "back" : "Summers in __Central Otago__ are hot with very high level of direct sunlight and a large diurnal range.",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "front" : "How does __Central Otago__ and its cool continental climate produce wines with high levels of alcohol?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEOC00Iul1k_SnS" : {
    "back" : "*Pinot Noir* accounts for 80% of plantings in __Central Otago__.\n\nOther varieties: *Pinot Gris*, *Chardonnay*, *Riesling*",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "front" : "What grape varieties are grown in __Central Otago__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEOC00Iul1k_SnU" : {
    "back" : "*Chenin Blanc* styles in __Loire Valley__ vary with ripeness level:\n\n1. grapes with low sugar ripeness go to sparkling wine production\n2. fully ripened grapes are used for dry wines\n3. over-ripe grapes are used for sweet wines",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "front" : "What *Chenin Blanc* styles are made in the __Loire Valley__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEPOm7gZ4fpGuOz" : {
    "back" : "*Melon Blanc*",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "front" : "What grape variety is referred to as *Muscadet* or *Melon de Bourgogne* in the __Loire Valley__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEPOm7gZ4fpGuP0" : {
    "back" : "*Muscadet Sèvre et Maine Sur Lie* are fermented in inert vessels, after which the wine spends the winter in contact with its *lees* in casks or tanks in contact.\n\nThe wine is bottled straight from the storage vessel in the following spring and may be filtered when bottled.\n\nContact with its lees increases the body of the wine and adds a yeasty complexity, and helps keep the wine fresh.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "front" : "How are *Muscadet Sevre et Maine Sur Lie* produced?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "tags" : ["fr", "loire", "viniculture"]
  },
  "-L576FEPOm7gZ4fpGuP2" : {
    "back" : "*White Sancerre* is a 100% *Sauvignon Blanc* style that is *bone dry*, *high in acidity*, and eschews *herbaceous* and *fruity* characteristics.\n\nSome villages (such as __Chavignol__) and vineyards (such as __Les Monts Damnés) have a reputation for *gun smoke* profile.",
    "front" : "Describe a *white Sancerre* wine.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "tags" : ["fr", "winestyle", "loire", "varietal", "sauvignon_blanc"]
  },
  "-L5Ak4j2_a_VEdzJn7PN" : {
    "back" : "__Loire__ *Sauvignon Blanc* do not reach the same level of ripeness that can be achieved in __New Zealand__'s bright sunshine.\n\nThe grapes are fermented at warmer temperatures and sometimes in old 600-litre wooden casks.",
    "front" : "What factors contribute to __Loire Valley__'s more restrained *Sauvignon Blanc* as compared to a __New Zealand__ style?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "tags" : ["fr", "loire", "varietal", "sauvignon_blanc", "climate", "viniculture"]
  },
  "-L5Ak4j8pBYyYQQxeqpc" : {
    "back" : "1. *Chenin Blanc*\n2. *Sauvignon Blanc*\n3. *Melon Blanc*",
    "front" : "Name __Loire Valley__'s most important white varietals.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "tags" : ["fr", "loire", "varietal", "chenin_blanc", "sauvignon_blanc", "melon_blanc"]
  },
  "-L576FEQTrF2txySBjIZ" : {
    "back" : "*Vouvray* (\"voo-vrae\") 100% *Chenin Blanc* white wines in a full range of styles - dry to sweet, still to pétillant to sparkling.\n\nColor ranges from *medium straw* (for sparkling wines) to *deep gold* (for aged sweet wines).\n\nAromas are *moderately intense*, with flavors of *pear*, *honeysuckle*, *quince*, and *apple*. Subtle notes of *ginger* and *beeswax* hint at presence of *noble rot* in certain vintages.\n\nFlavors range from *lean, dry, and minerally*, to *fruity and succulently sweet*, depending on the style.",
    "front" : "Describe *Vouvray* wines.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "winestyle", "loire", "varietal", "chenin_blanc"]
  },
  "-L576FEQTrF2txySBjIa" : {
    "back" : "__Nantais__ - Muscadet, Musacadet Sèvre et Maine, Musacadet Sèvre et Maine sur Lie\n\n__Anjou-Saumur__ - Anjou, Saumur, Coteaux du Layon, Savennières\n\n__Touraine__ - Touraine, Vouvray, Chinon, Bourgueil\n\n__Central Vineyards__ - Sancerre, Pouilly-Fumé, Menetou-Salon",
    "front" : "List the wine producing regions in the __Loire Valley__, from west to east, and list their key AC wines.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "geography", "law", "loire"]
  },
  "-L576FEQTrF2txySBjIc" : {
    "back" : "*Sauvignon Blanc*",
    "front" : "What grape variety is used in __Sancerre__ white wine?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "tags" : ["fr", "varietal", "sauvignon_blanc", "loire", "sancerre"]
  },
  "-L576FEQTrF2txySBjIe" : {
    "back" : "*Quarts de Chaume AC* and *Bonnezeaux AC* rank highly in the world for their sweet wines.\n\n*Botrytis* develops especially well in the Layon and adds body and texture to a fresh fruits style *Chenin Blanc* with high acidity and medium to medium+ alcohol (between 12-14%).",
    "front" : "Which two __Coteaux du Layon__ ACs are highly regarded for their *Botrytis* influenced sweet wines?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "winestyle", "chenin_blanc", "loire", "anjou_samur"]
  },
  "-L576FEQTrF2txySBjIg" : {
    "back" : "__Coteaux du Layon AC__ is a *sweet wine* made from *Chenin Blanc*, often affected by *botrytis*, but can also be very ripe or have sun-dried on the vine (*passerillé*).\n\nSeveral pickings are typical, with grapes becoming sweeter the later they are picked.\n\nGrapes are pressed and juice will slowly ferment due to high natural sugar levels.\n\nFermentation stops naturally when the alcohol level reaches 12-14%, leaving high levels of residual sugar with high levels of balancing acidity.",
    "front" : "How are __Coteaux du Layon AC__ wines produced?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "winestyle", "chenin_blanc", "loire", "anjou_samur"]
  },
  "-L576FEQTrF2txySBjIi" : {
    "back" : "*Sanvennieres* lies on the north bank of the *Loire Valley* in *Anjou Saumur*.\n\nAir circulation around the well-exposed vineyards impedes the development of *noble rot*, but enables late harvested *Chenin Blanc*  grapes to be used for full-bodied dry wines of exceptional complexity. ",
    "front" : "Where is *Sanvennieres* and what factors contribute to its sweet wines style?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "winestyle", "chenin_blanc", "loire", "anjou_samur"]
  },
  "-L576FEQTrF2txySBjIk" : {
    "back" : "Noble varieties that can be used to make VT, SGN and Grand Cru:\n- *Riesling*\n- *Gewurztraminer* \n- *Pinot Gris* \n- *Muscat* \nOther notable varieties: *Pinot Blanc*, *Pinot Noir* and *Sylvaner*.",
    "chapter" : "18",
    "front" : "Which grape varieties can be listed on *Alsace* wine labels?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "99",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZob" : {
    "back" : "*Alsace* has a*cool continental* climate, although the summers are hot and sunny, and autumns are dry and longer than is typical for this climate. *Vosges* mountains, to the west of Alsace shelds vineyards from westerly winds, making Alsace one of the driest regions in France. ",
    "chapter" : "18",
    "front" : "What is the climate of *Alsace*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "97",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZod" : {
    "back" : "*Alsace* has a great variety of soils:\n\nThe slopes include granitic, limestone, sandstone, clay, loam and volcanic soils.\n\nThe plains are largely alluvial.",
    "chapter" : "18",
    "front" : "What kind of the soils are prevalent in *Alsace*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "97",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZof" : {
    "back" : "The appellation system in *Alsace* is very simple - there are only two ACs for still wine:\n1. *Alsace AC* was created in 1962, and accounts for over 70 per cent of the wine producion of the region.\n2. *Alsace Grand Cru AC* was introduced in 1975. There are 51 vineyards with *Grand Cru* status.\nFurthermore, still wines can be classified as:\n- Vendange Tardive (VT) late harvest wines from the four noble varieties. Styles vary from dry to sweet and there can be some botrytis influence.\n- Selection de Grains Nobles (SGN): same grape varieties permitted as VT. Grapes are affected by noble rot and the wines will always be sweet.",
    "chapter" : "18",
    "front" : "How are still wines classified in *Alsace*?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "98",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZoh" : {
    "back" : "*Alsace* wines can be high in alcohol (14%+ abv) and retain an element of sweetness due to its long, sunny, dry summers and autumns.\n\nThese conditions are ideal for grapes to acquire high levels of sugar ripeness. This means that the yeast will be overcome by the alcohol before all the sugar is fermented. \n\nThe dry conditons also mean that *passerillage* is more common than *botrytis*, giving the wines a dried fruit character rather than the typical botrytis characters of honey and orange marmalade.",
    "chapter" : "18",
    "front" : "How are off-dry and sweet still white wines produced in *Alsace*?\n",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "99",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZoj" : {
    "back" : "*Loire Valley*'s climate ranges from cool*continental* in the *Central Vineyards* to Atlantic influenced *maritime* further downstream in *Anjou* andthe *Nantais*.\n\nVariations in the weather patterns from year to year means that vintages differ widely.",
    "chapter" : "19",
    "front" : "Describe *Loire Valley*'s climate.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "101",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZol" : {
    "back" : "Dry and sweet white wines principally made from Assyrtiko. ",
    "chapter" : "26",
    "front" : "What is grape variety for Santorini OPAP?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "135",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZon" : {
    "back" : "Red wines, made exclusively from Agiorgitiko.",
    "chapter" : "26",
    "front" : "What is grape variety for Nemea OPAP?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "135",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZop" : {
    "back" : "Tokaji harvest is by hand and there are three selesions made: Aszu, Szamorodni and healthy grapes.",
    "chapter" : "25",
    "front" : "What three selections of grape can make Tokaji?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "132",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZor" : {
    "back" : "Dry styles, Szamorodni, Aszu, Eszencia and Mordern style sweet wines",
    "chapter" : "25",
    "front" : "Describe Tokaji styles.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "132",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZot" : {
    "back" : "Starts with a base wine that is made from healthy grapes. Either during or after fermentation, the aszu berries are acerated in the base wine for up to 36 hours. Using uncrashed aszu berries avoids the extreaction of bitter flavours. Matured fro a minimum of three years, two of which must be in oak barrels. after which they develop an oxidative character. There is a trend to limit the impact of oxygen during maturation.",
    "chapter" : "25",
    "front" : "Describe Tokaji Aszu production.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "132",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZov" : {
    "back" : "Minimum of 180 g/L residual sugar is required.\n",
    "chapter" : "25",
    "front" : "How much residual sugar is required for Aszu Eszencia? ",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "133",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-L576FESNrFBSwq-YHAu" : {
    "back" : "The sweetest wines in the Aszu category are Aszu Ezsencia. Very rare and expensive and only made in the best years, grapes form the best vinyards. Tradtionally matured in barrels for between three and siz years, noticeable oxidative charater. There is now a trend among to age these wines for a shorter period to reduce the oxideative character of the wine. Tokaji is deep amber, with high acidity and intense aromas and flavours of orange marmalade, apricots and honey. Further complexities that hint at rye bread smoke, coffee and caramel. More concentrated and intense as they rise up the sweetness scale.",
    "chapter" : "25",
    "front" : "Describe the production of Aszu Eszencia.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "133",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-L576FESNrFBSwq-YHAw" : {
    "back" : "Fresher style of sweet wine they are now releasing top quality wines that fall outside of the Aszu category as noticeable new oak character as good and xpensive as Aszu wines.",
    "chapter" : "25",
    "front" : "Describe modern style sweet wines.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "133",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-L576FESNrFBSwq-YHAy" : {
    "back" : "",
    "chapter" : "",
    "front" : "How does a patent / continuous still work?\n(6 points)",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "",
    "status" : "inactive"
  },
  "-L576FESNrFBSwq-YHB-" : {
    "back" : "",
    "chapter" : "",
    "front" : "Describe the two ways in which producers are able to replicate hot maturation for **Madeira** wines.\n(6 points)",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "",
    "status" : "flagged"
  },
  "-L576FESNrFBSwq-YHB1" : {
    "back" : "",
    "chapter" : "",
    "front" : "List the 10 styles of red *Port*.\n(10 points)",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "",
    "status" : "inactive"
  },
  "-L576FESNrFBSwq-YHB3" : {
    "back" : "",
    "chapter" : "",
    "front" : "How is *Port* traditionally vinified and fortified?\n(6 points)",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "",
    "status" : "inactive"
  },
  "-L576FESNrFBSwq-YHB5" : {
    "back" : "Sherry is famous for its system of maturation called the solera system. The solera system is made up of a number of groups of butts, reffered to here as levels, which holds wines of different ages. These levels are called criadera and solera. The maturation process invovles moving wines between the levels. Theis is archived as below:\n- Wine of bottling or blending is taken out of the system from the level that holds wines of the oldest average called the solera.\n- The solera is not fully emptied and the butts are replenished with wine from another level that contains wine of a slightly younger average of age called the first criadera,\n- The first criadera is then replenished by wine from the second criadera and so on, each criadera being replenished with younger wine.\n- The criadera containing the youngest wine is usually replenished with sobretable wine.\nThe numbers of criadera can vary from as few as three to as many as fourteen.\nBy law producer may only take a third of the wine from a solera system in the course of a year.",
    "chapter" : "",
    "front" : "Describe how the *Solera* system works in the maturation of **Sherry**.\n(6 points)",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "",
    "status" : "inactive"
  },
  "-L576FETfrrYGcf_Pq-B" : {
    "back" : "- Traditional Method\n- Transfer Method\n- Tank Method\n- Asti Method\n- Carbonation",
    "chapter" : "",
    "front" : "What are five methods that can be used to make *sparkling* wines?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEU-8dS3tZxbmJM" : {
    "back" : "*Blanc de Blancs* in *Champagne* are made using 100% *Chardonnay*. \n\nIn youth they can be light bodied with high acidty with a restained citrus and green apple fruit character. With bottle age, the very best develop a rich buttery character.\n\nThere are both NV and Vintage Blanc de Blancs.",
    "chapter" : "",
    "front" : "Describe *Blanc de Blancs* in *Champagne*.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEVvqgyG5LN3a34" : {
    "back" : "1. Harvest and Pressing\n2. Primary Fermentation\n3. Blending\n4. Secondary Fermentation\n5. Yeast Autolysis\n6. Ridding\n7. Disgorgement and Corking\n8. Bottle Aging",
    "chapter" : "",
    "front" : "List the key steps in the \"Traditional Method\" for making *champagne*.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-L576FEVvqgyG5LN3a36" : {
    "back" : "",
    "chapter" : "",
    "front" : "List the *Mendoza* wine regions from the highest altitude to the lowest.\n(3 points)",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "",
    "status" : "flagged"
  },
  "-L576FEVvqgyG5LN3a38" : {
    "back" : "",
    "chapter" : "",
    "front" : "Describe the climate affecting grape growing in *Chile*.\n(6 points)",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "",
    "status" : "flagged"
  },
  "-L576FEVvqgyG5LN3a3A" : {
    "back" : "\n*Bourgogne Hautes-Côtes de Nuits AC* vintage takes place approx. 1 week later than on the main Côte, many in co-operative cellars in *Beaune*. \n\nThese wines are lighter in body and less concentrated than wines from the main villages of *Côtede Nuits*.",
    "chapter" : "",
    "front" : "What are the main differences comparing *Bourgogne Hautes-Côtes de Nuits AC* to the main *Côte de Nuits* villages?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["fr", "burgundy", "law"]
  },
}
